<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Yuuno Blog | ITP: Do we need to clean the environment of Open Source Community</title>
<icon>https://yuuno.cc//favicon.jpg</icon>
<link href="https://yuuno.cc/feeds/do-we-need-to-clean-oss-env.rss" rel="self"/>
<link href="https://yuuno.cc/articles/do-we-need-to-clean-oss-env"/>
<updated>2018-09-24T22:45:00.000Z</updated>
<id>do-we-need-to-clean-oss-env</id>
<author>
<name>Yuuno Hibiki</name>
</author>
<generator uri="https://github.com/NHibiki/ReSlice">ReSlice</generator>
<entry>
<title>ITP: Do we need to clean the environment of Open Source Community</title>
<link href="https://yuuno.cc/articles/do-we-need-to-clean-oss-env"/>
<id>do-we-need-to-clean-oss-env</id>
<published>2018-09-24T22:45:00.000Z</published>
<updated>2018-09-24T22:45:00.000Z</updated>
<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/science/elements/after-years-of-abusive-e-mails-the-creator-of-linux-steps-aside">Article</a> reveals what I've been annoying about these years in the Open Source Community (typically in Github). I am writing this article not to aim at some one or some 'group', but only to express what I thought and felt badly these years. Welcome to reply in any form of words.</p><p>It is always NOT SO CORRECT to judge one thing on one aspect. So as the Open Source Community. We should admit that the community has its own prosperous environment which might contents different kinds of people. It is like the 'political correctness' thing I do not want to talk further<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Political_correctness">[1]</a>. The essential thing is, whether the community meets the purpose that the community had when originally formed. Is <strong>Linux</strong> a good project? Yes, definitely. The lackness of the Linux former does not mean the Open Source Project itself is of defect.</p><p>So when it comes to the environment of Open Source Community. One point I believe is nessesary is that the <strong>Code of Conduct</strong> or ways of <strong>Contributions</strong> every project has, which guides people following the rules and fulfilling the project, should be responsible for both users and developers and others it relates to. And that is the project's purpose and duty. By mentioning <strong>responsible</strong>, it means project managers can appoint or specifies groups to assign tasks with, but should care about the outcome of contributors. Contributors also should respect the guidelines and contribution itself.</p><p>We usually see some abuse on Github. For example, some one pay for a bunch of people to collect stars for a meaningless project in order for a better winning rate in interview. Or some users use <strong>Issue</strong> to address meaningless blab. Those behavour can largely damage the principles of Open Source since they discourage users or developers. However, the case the article posts cannot be a real issue of <strong>abuse</strong>, this is a personal problem but has no relation with Open Source itself.</p><p>The natural basis of Open Source is to share and learn. And the project itself is the really most important thing.</p>]]></content>
<summary type="html">
The,Article,revealswhatI&#39;vebeenannoyingaboutthesey
</summary>
<category term="Essay" scheme="https://yuuno.cc/categories/Essay"/>
<category term="Assignment" scheme="https://yuuno.cc/tags/Assignment"/>
<category term="ITP" scheme="https://yuuno.cc/tags/ITP"/>
</entry>
</feed>