<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Yuuno Blog | ITP: Why would people engage in Open Source</title>
<icon>https://yuuno.cc//favicon.jpg</icon>
<link href="https://yuuno.cc/feeds/why-would-people-engage-in-os.rss" rel="self"/>
<link href="https://yuuno.cc/articles/why-would-people-engage-in-os"/>
<updated>2018-09-16T20:35:16.000Z</updated>
<id>why-would-people-engage-in-os</id>
<author>
<name>Yuuno Hibiki</name>
</author>
<generator uri="https://github.com/NHibiki/ReSlice">ReSlice</generator>
<entry>
<title>ITP: Why would people engage in Open Source</title>
<link href="https://yuuno.cc/articles/why-would-people-engage-in-os"/>
<id>why-would-people-engage-in-os</id>
<published>2018-09-16T20:35:16.000Z</published>
<updated>2018-09-16T20:35:16.000Z</updated>
<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After reading <a href="https://medium.com/processing-foundation/processing-and-floss-d35aa4607f4c">Processing and FLOSS</a>, I felt refreshed about what I have learned. Especially the point that the article mentioned about the Multipossibility of combined softwares <a href="https://medium.com/processing-foundation/processing-and-floss-d35aa4607f4c#90cd">[1]</a>.</p><blockquote><p>FLOSS software is an ecology where thousands of projects, large and small, can be combined in different ways to create new software.</p></blockquote><p>As I demostrated in my last reflection, I regard Open Source as <em>Idea Sharing</em>, which integrates different points of view on one tools or one project. But I cannot agree more that I miss up another essential significance of Open Source Project - the reuse of ideas and works. Besides the example that <em>Processing</em> takes advantages of <em>JNA</em>, <em>Apache Ant</em>, or <em>JUnit</em>. Many famous open source projects stand on multiple of other extraordinary, reusing their brilliant ideas and make them shinier.</p><p>Our great Open Source Community Github has a tab about the relation between projects (it might only available on some projects that use package management tools like <em>Maven</em>, <em>npm</em>, <em>yarn</em>, etc.) Inside one project, we can find a tab <strong>Insights</strong>, then go to <strong>Dependency Graph</strong> on the left. A fully detailed dependency graph is shown about the open source projects this project reuses and the other that base on this project. For example, the dependency of <a href="https://github.com/facebook/react/network/dependencies">React</a>.</p><p>And this is exactly the idea that owns <em>freedoms to modify and expand</em> anything<a href="https://medium.com/processing-foundation/processing-and-floss-d35aa4607f4c#09d4">[2]</a>. There is no best software and tool, but only the tool that fits one most. Open Source can realise people's dream on that.</p><p>Another great example is <strong>VIM</strong>, a controversial Text Editor. Many people addict to it is not for the design or difficulty for using (actually I find it really hard to manage in some ways), but for the self-manipulation and customization. As if one can write more efficient code with self-configured <strong>vim</strong> than any other IDE or Text Editor like <strong>Jet Brains</strong>, <strong>VS Code</strong>, <strong>Atom</strong>, etc. But others become a fool when they use this totally customized toy!</p><p>So for community, one can add any possibility to a great project and polish it. On the other hand, for self, any great Open Source Project can be a powerful arm to simplify its life.</p>]]></content>
<summary type="html">
Afterreading,ProcessingandFLOSS,,Ifeltrefreshedabo
</summary>
<category term="Essay" scheme="https://yuuno.cc/categories/Essay"/>
<category term="Assignment" scheme="https://yuuno.cc/tags/Assignment"/>
<category term="ITP" scheme="https://yuuno.cc/tags/ITP"/>
</entry>
</feed>